<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
 "concept.dtd">
<?Pub Sty _display FontColor="red"?>
<concept id="viewing_working_chats_chatdevice" xml:lang="en-us">
<title>Viewing and working with your chats and chat history</title>
<shortdesc>Using the Chats tab on the main application, you can view and organize open and closed
chats by date, search through your chats by name, and delete older chats.</shortdesc>
<conbody>
<p>On your Apple device, you can view an archived collection of your chats from the
<uicontrol>Chats</uicontrol> tab of the Connections Chat application. Once inside the Chats tab, the
following segmented views are available:</p>
<table frame="all" rowsep="1" colsep="1" id="table_chh_51c_rhb">
<title>Chat tab views</title>
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"/>
<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1*"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry>View</entry>
<entry>Description</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>Active</entry>
<entry>The Active chat tab lists all open chats, including single and group chats, ordered by
received time of latest message. <p>The rows display the contact name or the group chat subject as
the title, along with the last message in the conversation. </p><p>You can use the
<uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button at the top or side swipe a row to close the chats and remove them
from the list. </p></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>History</entry>
<entry>The History chat tab shows all chats, including active and closed ones, ordered
alphabetically by contact name. The first row lists multi-person chats, if any exist.<p>For an iPad,
you can use the Edit button at the top to delete a chat from the list. On an iPhone, you can swipe a
row to delete chats from the list. </p></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
</conbody>
<concept id="working_with_chathistory">
<title>Working with chat history </title>
<shortdesc>With the <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> view under the <uicontrol>Chats</uicontrol> tab,
you can view and manage the archived transcripts of all your chats, both open and closed. From here,
you can view either multi-person chats or single person chats.</shortdesc>
<conbody>
<p>To view multi-person chats, select the <uicontrol>Multi-Person Chat</uicontrol> row. Entries in
this view are listed by date, in reverse chronological order, with the titles showing the group chat
subject. Select any entry to open the conversation transcript for that day. You can use the
<uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button at the top to delete chats from the list. </p>
<p>To view transcripts of single person chats, select any of the contact names listed below the
Multi-Person Chat row. Doing so displays a list of the chat dates in which you had conversations
with that contact. Select one of the dates to open the transcript for that chat. You can use the
<uicontrol>Edit</uicontrol> button at the top to delete transcripts from the list. </p>
<p>In any of the history views, you can use the Search field to search your chats for a contact,
specific text within transcripts, a group chat participant, or the subject of a group chat. </p>
</conbody>
<concept id="configuring_chat_history">
<title>Configuring chat history </title>
<conbody>
<p>The chat history feature is enabled by default and can be configured in the Settings panel.
Select the sub-option <uicontrol>Chat History</uicontrol> to display the Chat History settings.
Press <uicontrol>Chat History</uicontrol> to turn the option on or off. The <uicontrol>Delete
History</uicontrol> button allows you to set how long chat transcripts should be saved. By default,
chat history never expires. </p>
</conbody>
</concept>
</concept>
</concept>
<?Pub *0000001020?>
