<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE concept PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DITA Concept//EN"
 "concept.dtd">
<?Pub Sty _display FontColor="red"?>
<concept id="viewing_working_chats_chatdevice" xml:lang="en-us">
<title>Viewing and working with your chats and chat history</title>
<shortdesc>Using the Chats tab on the main application, you can view and organize open and closed
chats by date, search through your chats by name, and delete older chats.</shortdesc>
<conbody>
<p>On your Android device, you can view an archived collection of your chats from the
<uicontrol>Chats</uicontrol> tab of the Connections Chat application. Once inside the Chats tab, the
following segmented views are available:</p>
<table frame="all" rowsep="1" colsep="1" id="table_chh_51c_rhb">
<title>Chat tab views</title>
<tgroup cols="2">
<colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"/>
<colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1*"/>
<thead>
<row>
<entry>View</entry>
<entry>Description</entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row>
<entry>Active</entry>
<entry>The Active chat tab lists all open chats, including one on one and group chat, ordered by the
received time of the latest message. <p>The first row lists multi-person chats, if any exist. All
other rows display the contact name as the title, along with the last message in the conversation
and the time it was received.</p><p>You can long press on a contact in any of the above lists to
display a menu with the contact's Business Card, and options for closing the chat. You can also add
the contact to your contacts list from here.</p></entry>
</row>
<row>
<entry>History</entry>
<entry>The History chat tab shows all chats, including active and closed ones, ordered
alphabetically by contact name. The first row lists multi-person chats, if any exist.</entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup>
</table>
<p>In any of the above views, you can use the Search field to search your chats by name. </p>
</conbody>
<concept id="working_with_chathistory">
<title>Working with chat history </title>
<shortdesc>With the <uicontrol>History</uicontrol> view under the <uicontrol>Chats</uicontrol> tab,
you can view and manage the archived transcripts of all your chats, both open and closed. From here,
you can view either multi-person chats or single person chats.</shortdesc>
<conbody>
<p>To view multi-person chats, select the <uicontrol>Multi-Person Chat</uicontrol> row. Entries in
this view are listed by the title of the group chat topic, with the sub-title being the last chat
message truncated with the chat date. Select any entry to open the conversation transcript. Chats
are grouped by date. Long press any chat to show the options for deleting it, or for deleting the
entire conversation. You can also select <uicontrol>Back</uicontrol> to return the parent view.</p>
<p>To view transcripts of single person chats, press any of the contact names listed in the parent
view below the Multi-Person Chat row. Doing so displays a list of the chat dates you have previously
chatted with that contact. Select one of the dates to open the transcript for that chat. Long press
any chat to show the options for deleting it, or for deleting the entire conversation. You can also
select <uicontrol>Back</uicontrol> to return the parent view.</p>
<note>Long pressing a chat date and selecting <uicontrol>Delete All</uicontrol> will delete all chat
histories for that person. Long pressing a person's name and selecting <uicontrol>Delete
All</uicontrol> will clear all chat history from the device, regardless of person. Selecting
<uicontrol>Delete</uicontrol> from a long press on a person's name will only delete the history for
that person.</note>
</conbody>
<concept id="configuring_chat_history">
<title>Configuring chat history </title>
<conbody>
<p>To use the chat history feature, you must enable it in the Chat settings dialog of the
configuration menu. From the Connections Chat configuration menu, select the
<uicontrol>Chat</uicontrol> settings button. Press <uicontrol>Enable chat history</uicontrol> at the
bottom to activate chat archiving. The <uicontrol>Delete history after</uicontrol> option allows you
to decide how long chat transcripts should be saved.</p>
</conbody>
</concept>
</concept>
</concept>
<?Pub *0000001020?>
